<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<ModMetaData>
	<name>TraderGen</name>
	<author>José Ángel Soler Ortiz</author>
	<supportedVersions>
		<li>1.3</li>
		<li>1.4</li>
	</supportedVersions>
	<url>https://gitlab.com/joseasoler/tradergen</url>
	<packageId>joseasoler.TraderGen</packageId>
	<description><![CDATA[TraderGen is a mod focused on improving trader variety. Every trader will feel different and unique, while fitting seamlessly with the world and mod selection of your current game.

In addition to their usual stock, orbital traders now have specializations. Specializations add a limited selection of stock matching a particular theme; even if they share a trader type an ordnance combat supplier will feel very different from a scavenger combat supplier. Orbital traders will now also get more diverse and fitting names.

With the Ideology DLC, traders will expand their stock depending on the ideoligion they follow. They may have their preferred apparel with their preferred ideology color in stock, or they may keep some of their venerated animals.

Memes also have unique effects in the trader stock. For example, tunneler ideologies will sell some insect meat and raw fungus, and Transhumanist traders will always purchase artificial body modifications and may have some of them in stock. TraderGen has support for more than 50 precepts from Ideology and multiple mods. Now every ideology will have a unique approach to trading!

TraderGen can also limit what traders are willing to purchase or stock depending on their ideology. This feature will affect the difficulty of the game, but it can be disabled in the mod settings. For example, non-cannibal ideologies will refuse to purchase human meat, while ideologies against cutting trees will not have wood in stock.

All of these stock modifications take into account the technological level of their trader. They are also intended to be fully compatible with your modlist (please make a bug report if it doesn't!) and should always generate stock that matches their theme. You can tweak TraderGen to your liking; every feature can be tweaked, enabled or disabled in the mod settings.

You can find a detailed description of specializations, ideology features, trader tweaks and mod compatibility features in the project website.
]]></description>
	<modDependencies>
		<li>
			<packageId>brrainz.harmony</packageId>
			<displayName>Harmony</displayName>
			<steamWorkshopUrl>steam://url/CommunityFilePage/2009463077</steamWorkshopUrl>
			<downloadUrl>https://github.com/pardeike/HarmonyRimWorld/releases/latest</downloadUrl>
		</li>
	</modDependencies>
	<loadAfter>
		<li>brrainz.harmony</li>
		<li>Ludeon.RimWorld</li>
		<li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Royalty</li>
		<li>Ludeon.RimWorld.Ideology</li>
	</loadAfter>
</ModMetaData>
