<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<Defs>
	<HugsLib.UpdateFeatureDef Abstract="true" Name="TraderGenUpdateFeature">
		<defName>TraderGenUpdateFeature</defName>
		<modNameReadable>TraderGen</modNameReadable>
		<modIdentifier>joseasoler.TraderGen</modIdentifier>
		<linkUrl>https://steamcommunity.com/sharedfiles/filedetails/?id=2804121197</linkUrl>
	</HugsLib.UpdateFeatureDef>
	<HugsLib.UpdateFeatureDef ParentName="TraderGenUpdateFeature">
		<defName>TraderGen_0_3_1</defName>
		<assemblyVersion>0.3.1</assemblyVersion>
		<content>
			<![CDATA[<color=#e1e150>Mod compatibility:</color>

• The synthetics orbital trader specialization has been updated for the latest <i>Rim-Robots_</i> release. It now sells synth upgrades, fuel nodes and a mechanent component. It may rarely have a mech-casket in stock.

• Fixed compatibility issues with the <i>Medieval Madness: Tools of the Trade</i> mod.
]]>
		</content>
	</HugsLib.UpdateFeatureDef>
	<HugsLib.UpdateFeatureDef ParentName="TraderGenUpdateFeature">
		<defName>TraderGen_0_3_0</defName>
		<assemblyVersion>0.3.0</assemblyVersion>
		<content>
			<![CDATA[<color=#e1e150>New features:</color>

• New orbital trader specialization, prospector. Sells a random selection of minable resources. In vanilla this includes steel, components, gold, jade, plasteel and uranium. It should also be compatible with all mods; for example it may have some gemstones with Jewelry, or sky steel with Alpha Animals. Present in bulk and orbital traders.

• Followers of the Tunneler or Industrialism memes will have some minable resources in stock. These are chosen from the same pool used by the prospector specialization.

<color=#e1e150>Mod compatibility:</color>

• <i>Trade UI Revised</i> now shows the specializations of orbital traders.

• A new orbital trader specialization is available with <i>Rim-Robots_</i>, synthetics. Sells prosthetics for mechanents and personae, fuel nodes and mechanite cores. It may sometimes have a mech-casket in stock. Present in exotic and slaver orbital traders. It is also present in prosthetics or bionics orbital traders added by other mods.

• <i>Cybernetic Organism and Neural Network</i> adds a bionics trader when Expanded Prosthetics and Organ Engineering or the Forked version are not included in the game. This trader now gets access to the drugs, hunting, medicine, organs, psycasting and wealth specializations. Now it will also purchase all prosthetics from any mods, and most really expensive items.

• With <i>Vanilla Factions Expanded - Settlers</i>, enemy caravans attacked during caravan raid events will have their stock influenced by TraderGen as well.
]]>
		</content>
	</HugsLib.UpdateFeatureDef>
	<HugsLib.UpdateFeatureDef ParentName="TraderGenUpdateFeature">
		<defName>TraderGen_0_2_0</defName>
		<assemblyVersion>0.2.0</assemblyVersion>
		<content>
			<![CDATA[This new version adds support for the Ideology DLC. It is safe to use it in existing 0.1.x savegames. Now traders will expand their stock depending on the ideoligion they follow. They may have their preferred apparel with their preferred ideology color in stock, or they may keep some of their venerated animals.

Memes also have unique effects in the trader stock. For example, tunneler ideologies will sell some insect meat and raw fungus, and Transhumanist traders will always purchase artificial body modifications and may have some of them in stock. TraderGen has support for more than 50 precepts from Ideology and multiple mods. Now every ideology will have a unique approach to trading!

TraderGen can also limit what traders are willing to purchase or stock depending on their ideology. This feature will affect the difficulty of the game, but it can be disabled in the mod settings. For example, non-cannibal ideologies will refuse to purchase human meat, while ideologies against cutting trees will not have wood in stock.

You can find a detailed list of all the ideology additions in the features page linked in the steam workshop website of TraderGen.

This version also adds a new orbital trader specialization. Scavengers sell steel, chemfuel, some components, and random scavenged items. They are present in bulk and combat orbital traders.
]]>
		</content>
	</HugsLib.UpdateFeatureDef>
</Defs>